<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Jonathan Giuffrida</title>
 <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-11-08T19:04:24-06:00</updated>
 <id>https://lucaluca.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jonathan Giuffrida</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Valuing the Liberal Arts</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/10/26/la/"/>
   <updated>2015-10-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/10/26/la</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;em&gt;Brooklyn Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;, I investigated various attempts to place a value on a liberal arts education, especially as contrasted with one in STEM alone. I interviewed Shirley Tilghman, President-emerita of Princeton, as a leader and public thinker on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;impact&quot;&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article, &amp;quot;Valuing the Liberal Arts&amp;quot;, was &lt;a href=&quot;http://brooklynquarterly.org/valuing-the-liberal-arts/&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in Issue 6 of &lt;em&gt;The Brooklyn Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pindar</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/08/01/Pindar/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/08/01/Pindar</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;These fragments I have shored against my ruins.
  &lt;div class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;T.S. Eliot &lt;a href=&quot;https://pindar.pythonanywhere.com/Pindar/default/quotes/91&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-external-link&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone with experience studying and working in the humanities, I know that quotes, or small pieces of text such as poems and song lyrics, are essential to self-expression for a very large number of people. Yet it seems that the Internet lacks a good place for people to collect and analyze small pieces of text and study how they interconnect. Pindar, named for one of the first Greek lyric poets, is an attempt to create that place, and a side project over the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pindar.pythonanywhere.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/pindar.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;border: 2px solid #999;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Intelligent, user-powered site for quote collection and analysis.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-scope&quot;&gt;Project scope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pindar differs from other quote sites in a number of important ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is 100% user-powered, meaning that actual people submit and vouch for every quote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is open source under the MIT license, making it free to use, copy, and contribute to the code base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes all data available via intelligent searching and an API for use in other applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is built from the ground up to be &lt;em&gt;smarter&lt;/em&gt;: quotes can be linked to each other on the basis of allusion, influence, and similar topics, and selected into user-created anthologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pindar also includes functionality you would expect, such as the ability to rate and comment on quotes, and edit all information submitted by other users for accuracy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pindar is built using the Python framework web2py, which helps quickly create complex sites, and hosted by PythonAnywhere. The concept and initial code was a collaboration between me and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mrbeskin&quot;&gt;mrbeskin&lt;/a&gt;, and the current version is by me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the quotes on this site link to their pages on Pindar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;impact&quot;&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pindar is built to scale, and we have many more features under development. Join us! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn&quot; href=&quot;https://pindar.pythonanywhere.com&quot; style=&quot;padding: 10px 20%;&quot;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
To help build a better home for quotes, visit Pindar on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lucaluca/Pindar&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Someone wrote about me</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/07/01/writeup/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/07/01/writeup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://harris.uchicago.edu/news-and-events/features/student-campus-news/mastering-art-and-science-data-visualization&quot;&gt;Mastering the Art (and Science) of Data Visualization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Blobs, or Smart Clusters</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/06/15/Blobs/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/06/15/Blobs</id>
   <content type="html"></content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Harris Insider</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/06/01/Harris-Insider/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/06/01/Harris-Insider</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;some stuff about me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;intro-paragraph-about-harris-evaluations&quot;&gt;intro paragraph about harris evaluations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&amp;#39;s-important?&quot;&gt;what&amp;#39;s important?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easy to access and use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;balance between too much and too little information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stakeholders: students, faculty, administration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fairness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-i-make-it?&quot;&gt;how did i make it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drupal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jQuery and Highcharts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d3 splash page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&amp;#39;s-the-impact?&quot;&gt;what&amp;#39;s the impact?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22,000 evaluations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changing the way courses are launched and reviewed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write-up of me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;takeaway?&quot;&gt;takeaway?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this isn&amp;#39;t hard to do!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use language from the writeup of me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Social Determinants of Health in Chicago's Community Areas</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/02/28/SDH/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-28T23:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2015/02/28/SDH</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As an Innovation Fellow at the Chicago Department of Public Health, I was asked to find a way to visualize how social determinants&amp;mdash;a combination of a community&amp;#39;s economic and social characteristics, the built environment, and people&amp;#39;s behaviors&amp;mdash;influence health and wellness. The result is an interactive scatterplot that helps users visualize any combination of these variables in Chicago&amp;#39;s 77 community areas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lucaluca.github.io/SDH&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/healthychiviz2.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Interactive scatterplot of social determinants and health outcomes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-scope&quot;&gt;Project scope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social determinants of health are increasingly being recognized as critical to understanding and improving the health of communities. Some, such as air quality and access to fresh foods, have very clear effects on health; others like rent burden (spending &amp;gt;30% of income on rent), tree density, and unemployment have less clear impacts on health. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because so many new associations between social determinants and health outcomes are beginning to be discovered and studied, health policy analysts and public health officials need ways to explore large numbers of possible associations in a way that is clear, easy to interpret, and not too visually complex. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borrowing from &lt;a href=&quot;http://bl.ocks.org/msbarry/9911363&quot;&gt;this visualization of WHO data&lt;/a&gt;, I built an interactive scatterplot that allows users to plot Chicago&amp;#39;s community areas using any three demographic, social determinant, health behavior, or health outcomes on the X and Y axes and as the size of the points. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of features were included to meet the needs of health care professionals, the intended audience. The 100+ indicators were grouped into categories, and those that were rates clearly state their units. Hovering over a bubble shows which community area is represented and its values along all three selected variables, and a table below the chart shows summary statistics. The bubbles are colored according to regions of the city, and users can highlight entire regions to focus on. A few examples, such as the &amp;ldquo;Hispanic Paradox&amp;rdquo;, guide the user through some relationships between social determinants and health outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/healthychiviz3.png&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hovering over a bubble reveals information about that community area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scatterplot is built in &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org/&quot;&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful JavaScript library for visualization. Thanks to GitHub Pages, building and hosting it is 100% free, and the code is open source on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lucaluca/SDH&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and free for others to use or modify. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;impact&quot;&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scatterplot has received very positive feedback from a number of public health departments, providers, collaborative groups, and research institutions. It is frequently shown in presentations and meetings as an example of a powerful yet simple way to visualize complex data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a city like Chicago, communities with high levels of hardship often face difficulties in many areas at the same time, such as high unemployment, poor public transportation, and reduced access to healthcare. Lightning strikes these same neighborhoods every single day. Hopefully, visualizations like these can start and fuel important conversations and deeper analyses of interconnections that degrade Chicago residents&amp;#39; ability to lead healthy lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Plenario</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/09/23/Plenario/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/09/23/Plenario</id>
   <content type="html"></content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Data in Public Policy</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/09/01/DIPP/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/09/01/DIPP</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A website that looks suspiciously like my own.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mapping Pedestrian and Cyclist Fatalities</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/07/10/pedestrians/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/07/10/pedestrians</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cars and trucks&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Spatial Analysis of Crime in Bogotá</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/06/30/wb/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/06/30/wb</id>
   <content type="html"></content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chicago Policy Review Data Visualization</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/05/01/CPR/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/05/01/CPR</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A website that looks suspiciously like my own.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Price Inflation in Venezuela in Two Charts</title>
   <link href="https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/02/24/venezuela/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-24T23:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>https://lucaluca.github.io/project/2014/02/24/venezuela</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Venezuela&amp;#39;s inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
